in this video
we'll take a look at the documentation
that's available on the postgres website
and see how easy it is to find out more
information about the sql syntax that it
supports its functionality
and much much more now this is the
postgres homepage here and where you'll
want to go is to documentation
in the main navigation and then once you
get to here you want to look in the
right side here and find the version
that matches the version of postgres
that you're currently using
now i have 9.4.6 installed so i'll go to
9.4
and you can choose with or without
comments either one is fine
and now once you get to this point this
is the main index of the documentation
and you can scroll down and see in the
table of contents all the different
things
that are included in here but i find
what's most helpful is just to go to the
search box and then
search for whatever it is that you're
looking for i just searched for select
because i'm curious about
exactly what does postgres support in
terms of a select sql statement
and then here it's the first result
select and now on this page i can read a
whole lot of information about
exactly how i can write a select
statement and also how that's going to
be interpreted by
the postgres database when i execute the
statement
now this first box at the top this
contains a description of the
specific syntax that you need to use in
order to successfully create a
statement of this type and there's a
little bit that you need to know about
how to read this now
it can be kind of overwhelming but it's
good to be able to look at this listing
and figure out exactly where to go next
to find out more information
so when you're looking at one of these
syntax printouts
anything that's inside square brackets
is something that's optional so if you
see square brackets around something
that means that whatever is inside it
you may or may not actually need to
include and that's why if you see this
whole first line is inside square
brackets
however select on the next line is not
so a select statement has to include
the term select that kind of makes a lot
of sense
now likewise if you're looking through
this listing and you see something that
is in
curly braces like this that means that
you have to choose
one of these things in between so you'd
have to use at least one of these
in order to use the syntax that's in
this listing
now this particular piece of the select
statement syntax is only used
if you're using either union intersect
or accept to join multiple select
statements together
and in that case you would need to use
at least union intersect or
accept in order to do that properly now
that's not something that we're going to
be doing in this course
but down here under limit that is
something that we'll look at
and so this shows that the entire limit
clause is optional because it's in
square brackets
and then inside there you you have to
use the term limit if you're going to
use this
at all and then you either have to have
a count
or the term all to complete that clause
and most commonly what you'll say is
limit and then a number limit 10 limit
20.
sometimes even limit 1 if you just want
to get one result back
now you'll also notice in the syntax
printout there are some terms that are
printed in a different way they're bold
and italicized
such as with query expression output
name
and now if you see something like that
what that means is that there's going to
be more information about that
term somewhere in the page later so
in one example would be the from item
right here and you'll see that there's
actually a portion of the page here
where it says
where from item can be one of and so
this tells you that
where you see from item you would
actually replace that with one of these
options
some of these terms for example
expression or condition those
are not listed in this listing but if
you look later in the page
underneath whatever part of the
statement they show up under you can
usually find out more information
so for example let's try to find out
more about condition
and so i'll scroll down the page
and here under the where clause which is
where it appeared in the syntax
you'll see information about the
condition and what that actually means
so the postgres documentation is a good
resource to get used to using
there is a lot of information in here
and because postgres is very powerful
and has a lot of features
it can be overwhelming when you're
looking at something like this and just
trying to figure out how to write a
select statement
but for the most part you can kind of
pick through it find the things that
you're looking for
and it can be a big help when you're
trying to figure out exactly how to make
something work
now of course there are plenty of other
resources on the internet that you can
use
such as stock overflow or your favorite
search engine and these things can
always help you find solutions to
problems that you're running into in
your projects
but it's always good to become
comfortable with the documentation
for a software package that you're using
and the postgres documentation is
excellent
and i highly recommend checking it out
as you're developing your projects